اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ
This Queen was, what we call today; very democratic or shuraa(شوری) a better word; She would seek the advice of her followers.
And Subhan Allah(سُبْحان الله)! We see in this Queen many good qualities before Islam.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى guided her through her Hikmah(حكمة).
You can see from her personality; that she was very wise and her wisdom ended up leading her into Islam.
Because Al-Aqal(العقل); the mind would lead us toward truth, would lead us to understand the message of the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء); by the will of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And that's why; the non-believers on the day of judgment, no matter how intelligent they were on the face of the earth,
on the day of judgment when they see the punishment and they see hellfire; what would they say?
وَقَالُواْ لَوْ كُنَّا نَسْمَعُ أَوْ نَعْقِلُ مَا كُنَّا فِىٓ أَصْحَٰبِ الْجَحِيم۝
They would say; If we used to hear, or if we had understanding; we wouldn't have been in hellfire.
So they say; we didn't have any understanding when we're on earth, and we didn't have any hearing.
So the true mind and the true understanding; is the understanding that would lead a person towards the truth or lead the person towards Islam.
She was soliciting advice from her Mala'(مَلَاْ);
Al-Mala'(اَلْمَلَاْ) in Qur'an means; the chiefs or the leaders of the society, Al-Mala'(اَلْمَلَاْ).
قَالَتْ يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلْمَلَؤُاْ أَفْتُونِى فِىٓ أَمْرِى
She said; Oh chiefs! Advise me in this case of mine.
And then she said;
مَا كُنتُ قَاطِعَةً أَمْرًا حَتَّىٰ تَشْهَدُونِ۝
I decide no case to you are present with me and give me your opinions.
She said; I want your advice on this case.
And then she said; and you know me, I never take a decision until I seek your advice; Shuraa(شوری).
Their response was;
قَالُواْ نَحْنُ أُوْلُواْ قُوَّةٍۢ وَأُوْلُواْ بَأْسٍۢ شَدِيدٍۢ
They said; We have great strength and great ability for war.
They said, if you want us to fight, we're ready; The army is prepared; It's powerful; We're ready to go to war.
And then they said;
وَٱلْأَمْرُ إِلَيْكِ فَٱنظُرِى مَاذَا تَأْمُرِينَ۝
But it is for you to command, so think over what you will command.
So their opinion was; we are ready to do whatever you want us to do.
If you want us to fight; we're ready to fight.
So they gave her the green light to go to war.
Actually, maybe they encouraged her; they said; we are ready to fight, it's your decision now.
Her wisdom now shows up.
She wants to deal with the situation in the softest way possible.
And confrontation could be an option, but later.
Why start with confrontation when there are other means?
And we know that, that was the policy of Rasool Allah ﷺ in dealing with situations.
Rasool Allah ﷺ was described as;
ما خيربين أمرين إلا أختار أيسرهما
Whenever Rasool Allah ﷺ would be offered two options, he would always choose the easiest.
Rasool Allah ﷺ would try to avoid confrontation, whether it is with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) or any other people as much as he can.
And this was the way of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And that's why, when in Sulh al-Hudaybiyah(صلح الحديبية); an agreement was reached.
Rasool Allah ﷺ accepted it even though, many of Sahabahرضى الله عنهم were reluctant to accept it.
Because they felt that we're ready to fight.
But we should not understand that this means, we give our principles
or we compromise in the religion, as we find in the peace process that's happening now.
That's something different.
That is not peace; It is giving up; all of your principles and giving up; the Muslim land.
That's not called peace.
It's misleading; the naming itself is misleading.
What was the response of Al-Malikah(الملكه); the queen?
She said;
قَالَتْ إِنَّ ٱلْمُلُوكَ إِذَا دَخَلُواْ قَرْيَةً أَفْسَدُوهَا وَجَعَلُوٓاْ أَعِزَّةَ أَهْلِهَآ أَذِلَّةً ۖ وَكَذَٰلِكَ يَفْعَلُونَ۝
She said; Verily kings; when they enter a town, they despoil it and make the most honorable amongst its people; the lowest.
And then Allahسُبحانه وتعالى approved what she said and said;
And thus they do;
وَكَذَٰلِكَ يَفْعَلُونَ۝
What did she mean by this?
When the Kings enter into our land, they corrupt it.
She means that, when you enter into a confrontation with another nation; king or president or government whatever,
when you enter into confrontation with another state or nation,
and the other nation wins through war; when they entered into the land, they would occupy it.
And they would disrupt the system that was there because; they entered by force.
And because they were fighting another government.
Because who's the one who took the decision to fight; is the government.
They would make that government and the king or whoever is in position of responsibility; the lowest.
Because they are our enemy; I won against you; you were the one was fighting me; you're going to be the lowest, most likely they killed them.
But then they need assistance from the local people.
So who do they promote?
They usually promote the lowest class, who are enemies of the former government.
And that's something that you find always in wars between states.
So the Queen over here is saying; If we enter into a war with Sulaimanعليه السلام and he wins through war,
then us; the government, we're going to be done with, he's going to get rid of us.
And he's going to take our land as; Ghaneemah(غنيمه), he's going to invade our land and occupy it.
And he will do corruption to our land, because she is assuming that Sulaiman(سليمان) is like any other King.
She doesn't know that Sulaiman(سليمان) is different, he's a Nabi(نَبِي) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And we find; how corrupt the Muslim lands were under the European occupation.
And now we are still suffering from that corruption until this moment.
Because they entered through a state of war.
So she said; I will send them a gift, rather than fighting them.
وَإِنِّى مُرْسِلَةٌ إِلَيْهِم بِهَدِيَّةٍۢ فَنَاظِرَةٌۢ بِمَ يَرْجِعُ ٱلْمُرْسَلُونَ۝
But verily, I'm going to send him a present, and see with what answer the messengers return.
This method of dealing really shows her intelligence.
Because; it's going to work, if Sulaimanعليه السلام was not a prophet.
Because, why do kings invade lands?
Why do governments go in war to other countries?
Money;
to take that land as a Ghaneemah(غنيمه).
So she wants to send a gift, to Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان),
to convince him that, we're going to pay you rather than go to war with us and spend a lot of money in war;
we're going to give you whatever you want here, I'll send you a gift and see what your response will be.
She called it a gift.
We can maybe call it a gift, but it seems that's it's little bit tilting towards being a bride.
And as she said; I will see what happens.
فَنَاظِرَةٌۢ بِمَ يَرْجِعُ ٱلْمُرْسَلُونَ۝
I'm going to see, what the response is.
فَلَمَّا جَآءَ سُلَيْمَٰنَ
So when the messengers with the present came to Sulaiman(سليمان);
قَالَ أَتُمِدُّونَنِ بِمَالٍۢ
Sulaimanعليه السلام said; Will you help me in wealth?
فَمَآ ءَاتَىٰنِۦَ ٱللَّهُ خَيْرٌ مِّمَّآ ءَاتَىٰكُم
What Allah has given me, is better than what He has given to you.
Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) said; Are you trying to give me money?
He said; first of all what Allah has given me is better than what you have.
What can you offer me?
And many of the Mufassireen(مفسرين) say that, Sulaimanعليه السلام here was not referring to the material possessions that he has.
Even though, his material possessions are better than theirs.
But Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام was referring to the Nabuwwah(نبوّة) that Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has given him; the prophet-hood and the Ilm(علم) of religion.
What I have is better than, what you have. And then he said;
بَلْ أَنتُم بِهَدِيَّتِكُمْ تَفْرَحُونَ۝
You are the ones who are happy with gifts.
You cannot buy me with this gift.
This gift is not what will make me happy and pleasant.
You are the ones who can be bought off by gifts.
Gifts make you happy, but this strategy will not work with me.
And then Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام said;
ٱرْجِعْ إِلَيْهِمْ فَلَنَأْتِيَنَّهُم بِجُنُودٍۢ لَّا قِبَلَ لَهُم بِهَا وَلَنُخْرِجَنَّهُم مِّنْهَآ أَذِلَّةً وَهُمْ صَٰغِرُونَ۝
He said;
Then Solomon; Sulaiman(سليمان) said to the Chief of her messengers, who brought the present;
Go back to them, we verily shall come to them, with hosts that they cannot resist,
and we shall drive them out of their land in disgrace, and they will be abased.
Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) said; Go back and tell her, that we are going to send her an army that she will not be able to resist,
and we are going to drive them out of their land in a state of humility.
Sulaimanعليه السلام said; Don't give me these gifts; take your gifts back and we refused the gifts.
So the messengers went back to her and told her; he refused the gifts.
She realized; this was the first step in her realizing that, this man is not a man of Duniyah(دُنِيَّا).
He's not a man of this world; he's not seeking Duniyah(دُنِيَّا); he's up to something else.
And that was the first step for her to come towards the religion.
She decided not to go to war.
Even though, Sulaimanعليه السلام gave her a clear threat.
She decided; she's not going to go to war, and she's going to go and meet him personally.
She prepared her delegation, and they went out to meet with Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) when she was on her way, said to his chiefs;
قَالَ يَٰٓأَيُّهَا ٱلْمَلَؤُاْ أَيُّكُمْ يَأْتِينِى بِعَرْشِهَا قَبْلَ أَن يَأْتُونِى مُسْلِمِينَ۝
He said; Oh chiefs! Which of you can bring me her throne, before they come to me surrendering themselves in obedience?
What did the Hudhud(هدهد) describes; what did the bird describe in the kingdom of Saba'(سَبَإٍ)?
He describe the throne.
The throne was the symbol of their kingdom.
The throne was their pride.
This was a unique thing that only the kingdom of Saba'(سَبَإٍ) had; it was the symbol of their kingdom.
Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) said; Bring it to me, before they come to me.
Now you might ask the question; how come Sulaimanعليه السلام wanted to bring the throne; What's the reason?
Well, the scholars; the Mufassireen(مفسرين) have responded to that; They said;
that Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام wanted to show her miracle.
The Ambiyaaعليهم السلام; they exhibit their miracles in front of the people to prove the authenticity of the message.
They do that; one of the methods they do that; is through the miracles; presenting the miracles to the society.
And we know that something unique about Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام was his kingdom.
هَبْ لِى مُلْكًا لَّا يَنۢبَغِى لِأَحَدٍۢ مِّنۢ بَعْدِىٓ ۖ
Oh Allah! Give me a kingdom, that will occur to nobody after me.
So the kingdom of Sulaiman(سليمان) was his miracle.
And he wanted to present to her; some of the powers that are under his control by the will of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى
to show her that, he's a Nabi(نَبِي) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And he's not just a king.
Because, this was something out of the capability of kings in that time.
So he wanted to bring the throne before she arrives.
The first offer was made by; Ifreet min-al-Jinn(عِفْرِيتٌ مِّنَ ٱلْجِنِّ).
Ifreet(عِفْرِيت) is a name given to somebody who has excelled in his field and reached to the highest levels; it's called Ifreet(عِفْرِيت).
So, Ifreet min-al-Jinn( عِفْرِيتٌ مِّنَ ٱلْجِنِّ); Ifreet(عِفْرِيت) of the Jinn(جِن) who is at the highest levels of power among the Jinn(جِن).
You call that Jinn(جِن); Ifreet(عِفْرِيت).
So, he's not just a Jinn(جِن), but he's Ifreet(عِفْرِيت) from the Jinn(جِن); powerful Jinn(جِن).
And the word nowadays, in Arabic has been always used in reference to Jinn(جِن),
but in the Arabic language, it could mean; somebody who has excelled and reached very high level in that particular field.
Ifreet min-al-Jinn(عِفْرِيتٌ مِّنَ ٱلْجِنِّ); he made an offer. He said;
قَالَ عِفْرِيتٌ مِّنَ ٱلْجِنِّ أَنَا۠ ءَاتِيكَ بِهِۦ قَبْلَ أَن تَقُومَ مِن مَّقَامِكَ ۖ
وَإِنِّى عَلَيْهِ لَقَوِىٌّ أَمِينٌ۝
Ifreet(عِفْرِيت), a strong one from the Jinn(جِن) said; I will bring it to you before you rise from your place,
and verily I am indeed strong and trustworthy for such work.
His credentials; his resume was that I'm strong and trustworthy, and I can bring it to you before you rise up from your council.
It is said that, Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام used to sit in Majlis al-Qadha(مجلس القضا); his government seat; his throne.
He used to sit in it from Fajr(فجر) until Dhuhr(ظهر).
So depend it on, when this offer was made.
We can know that it's a few hours.
And from Yemen to Jerusalem is maybe four hours flight by airplane; four or five hours; That's how long it would take by air.
So this Ifreet(عِفْرِيت) was around that speed.
Allah-u-Aalam(اللَّهُ أَعْلمَ) exactly; how long it was; but they say that, he used to sit between Fajr(فجر) until Dhuhr(ظهر).
Even though, according to the standards of that time;
this was something that was out of the reach of anyone, to bring it in a few hours when the methods of transportation in their time was horse and camel.
Nevertheless, there was a better offer and Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام turned this offer down.
A few hours was not enough.
Because he got another offer from;
الَّذِي عِندَهُ عِلْمٌ مِّنَ الْكِتَابِ
The one who has knowledge of the book.
And this shows you the power of knowledge.
The one who has knowledge, had a better offer than the Ifreet(عِفْرِيت) of the Jinn(جِن).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
قَالَ الَّذِي عِندَهُ عِلْمٌ مِّنَ الْكِتَابِ أَنَا آتِيكَ بِهِ قَبْلَ أَن يَرْتتَدَّ إِلَيْكَ طَرْفُكَ ۚ
One with whom, who has knowledge of the Scriptures said;
I will bring it to you within the twinkling of an eye.
Before your eye blinks; the throne is going to be in front of you.
Ilm(علم); we know that, it's knowledge.
What type of knowledge?
We don't know.
Because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said; Al-Kitab(الكتاب); the Scripture.
What scripture?
Was it a scripture of Dawood(داؤد); Whether it was a different scripture; What exactly?
We do not involve in this discussion, because this is Ghayb(غيب); it is unknown.
What we know is; what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى told us in Qur'an, and we do not follow the Israiliyat(اسرائيليات) stories.
We don't go after that, but we stop at what information, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has provided us with.
We know that it's knowledge and we learned from this;
That knowledge, has power.
With the twinkling of an eye; the throne was right there in front of Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
This is power under the hands of Sulaiman(سليمان).
What was the response of Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام?
فَلَمَّا رَآهُ مُسْتَقِرًّا عِندَهُ قَالَ هَٰذَا مِن فَضْلِ رَبِّي لِيَبْلُوَنِي أَأَشْكُرُ أَمْ أَكْفُرُ ۖ
When he saw it placed before him, he said; This is by the grace of my Lord.
He didn't say; this is by the grace of the one who has knowledge.
He said; this is by the grace of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
That's why it's very important for us always, to believe and to say; whatever good I have done, is from Allah.
And whatever mistakes I have done; are from myself.
Whatever good we do, or happens to us, or anybody does; is from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
And then, Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) said;
لِيَبْلُوَنِي أَأَشْكُرُ أَمْ أَكْفُرُ ۖ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is testing me to see; whether I am grateful or ungrateful.
Whatever Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has given you; and we talked about this a lot.
Whatever Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has given you; is a test from Allah for you to see; if you will be grateful or not.
And then, he said;
وَمَن شَكَرَ فَإِنَّمَا يَشْكُرُ لِنَفْسِهِ ۖ
And whoever is grateful, truly his gratitude is for who?
For his own self.
You're not going to benefit Allahسُبحانه وتعالى at all, by being grateful to him; you're benefiting yourself.
وَمَن كَفَرَ فَإِنَّ رَبِّي غَنِيٌّ كَرِيمٌ۝
Whoever is ungrateful; certainly my lord is rich; free of all needs and bountiful.
If you are not grateful; believe me; Allahسُبحانه وتعالى does not need you.
We need to tell ourselves this; because sometimes we feel that the money we pay; we're doing a favour to the religion of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Whatever we donate of our time, or effort to the religion of Allah, sometimes we brag about it.
The religion of Allah does not need me; it does not need you; it does not need anyone.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is sufficient of all means.
We are doing this for our own benefit.
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام said;
قَالَ نَكِّرُواْ لَهَا عَرْشَهَا
He said; Disguise her throne for her; change the outlook of the throne a little bit.
Make some alterations to it.
Why?
قَالَ نَكِّرُواْ لَهَا عَرْشَهَا نَنظُرْ أَتَهْتَدِىٓ أَمْ تَكُونُ مِنَ ٱلَّذِينَ لَا يَهْتَدُونَ۝
To see; will she be one of those, who recognize it, or she would be one of those, who won't?
So they made some alterations to her throne; change the way it looks; a little bit.
But the essence of it, was the same.
The uniqueness and the greatness of that throne was untouched.
فَلَمَّا جَآءَتْ قِيلَ أَهَٰكَذَا عَرْشُكِ ۖ
So when she came; it was said to her; Is your throne like this?
This is a straightforward question.
Yes or no; question.
Is this your throne?
What should the answer be?
Yes or no.
Now she said; Yes!
It looks like our throne, but it's a little bit different.
And if she said; No!
It's true that there is some alterations to it, but it's very, very similar to my throne.
So, she avoided the yes or no answer, and she said;
قَالَتْ كَأَنَّهُۥ هُوَ ۚ
A very diplomatic answer.
She said;
It is as though, it were the very same.
So, it's not a yes answer, and it's not a no answer.
And this is part of her wisdom and Hikmah(حكمة).
She didn't give a straight answer of yes or no, and she made her answer right in between.
Because; it looks like her throne but it's a little bit different.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَأُوتِينَا ٱلْعِلْمَ مِن قَبْلِهَا وَكُنَّا مُسْلِمِينَ۝
Sulaimanعليه السلام said; Knowledge was bestowed on us before her, and we were submitting to Allah.
وَصَدَّهَا مَا كَانَت تَّعْبُدُ مِن دُونِ ٱللَّهِ ۖ إِنَّهَا كَانَتْ مِن قَوْمٍۢ كَٰفِرِينَ۝
And that what she used to worship besides Allah, has prevented her from Islam, for she was of a disbelieving people.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is saying; What prevented her from being a Muslim is, because the way; she was brought up.
Refusing the gift was one step for her towards Islam.
Bringing the throne was a second step for her, towards Islam.
قِيلَ لَهَا ٱدْخُلِى ٱلصَّرْحَ ۖ
It was said to her, Enter As-Sarkh(اَلصَّرْح).
What is As-Sarkh(اَلصَّرْح).?
As-Sarkh(اَلصَّرْح) is a special palace that was built for Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
This palace had very amazing things in it.
One of which was the flooring of this palace.
The floor was made out of glass; transparent glass, and under that glass was a flowing river.
So this palace is erected on water, and the floor was glass.
Glass was something that the people in that time might not have known; this transparent material.
So when, Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام told her to enter into this palace.
When she saw it; what did she think?
She thought it was water; so she raised up her skirt.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
قِيلَ لَهَا ٱدْخُلِى ٱلصَّرْحَ ۖ
فَلَمَّا رَأَتْهُ حَسِبَتْهُ لُجَّةً وَكَشَفَتْ عَن سَاقَيْهَا ۚ
But when she saw it; she thought it was a pool, and she tucked up her clothes uncovering her legs.
Something very embarrassing.
Why is it embarrassing?
Because, it shows her ignorance.
It shows that, she's backward considering the advanced age that Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) was at.
She doesn't know about this technology.
She was raising up her skirt, trying to walk into that water.
So it was embarrassing for her.
Why did Sulaiman(سليمان) do all of this?
Again to show her, what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has given him?
It's part of the miracle of what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has given him, to show to her, the truth of His message.
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام told her;
قَالَ إِنَّهُۥ صَرْحٌ مُّمَرَّدٌ مِّن قَوَارِيرَ ۗ
He said; Verily it is a glass surface with water underneath it.
In that moment, that was the third step towards Islam for her.
Finally, finally Bilqees(بلقيس) submitted and said;
قَالَتْ رَبِّ إِنِّى ظَلَمْتُ نَفْسِى وَأَسْلَمْتُ مَعَ سُلَيْمَٰنَ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَٰلَمِينَ۝
She said; My Lord!
Verily, I have wronged myself, and I submit to Allah; the Lord of Al-Alameen(اَلْعَٰلَمِينَ); the Lord of the world and she became a Muslim.
That's the end of the story in Qur'an.
And again, we don't go beyond that.
Because, there's many fairy tales about; what happened after that.
And there is no proof of the authenticity of any of these stories.
They say that Sulaimanعليه السلام married Bilqees(بلقيس) and it is turned into a romantic story.
And we do not again, get in this, because if it's not true, it is being very disrespectful with the Ambiyaa(أنبِيَاء) of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
So we avoid it completely.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى again; whatever has been mentioned in Qur'an is for us to learn the lessons from, Al-Ibrah(العبرة).
And whatever has not been mentioned in Qur'an; has not been mentioned because, there's no Ibrah(عبرة) in it, there's no lesson in it.
And we need to be practical and learn what will benefit us, Al-Ilm an-Nafia(اَلْعِلْمَ النّافِعَ); the beneficial knowledge.
And get away from the knowledge; that doesn't do us any good, and doesn't have any practicality or applications for it.
Essence of the story is that; at the end, Bilqees(بلقيس) became a Muslim, after she saw; what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has given Sulaimanعليه السلام.
We move on to another part of the story of Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
In the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ and until now, a lot of things have been attributed to Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام, which are untrue.
One of which, is magic.
There are some of Al-Yahood(اليهود); the Jews, who attribute magic to Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان),
and the whole story of the temple also, is attributed to Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
For example, the Jews, or the people of the book.
They associate Sulaimanعليه السلام with someone called; Asmodeus.
A S M O D E U S
And this Asmodeus was the chief of the devils.
And they associate him with Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام,
and they say that this devil; chief of the devils was the one who assisted Sulaiman(سليمان) in building and constructing.
And he is the one, who used to tutor and teach Sulaiman(سليمان) magic.
And to teach him many of the skills that they say, Sulaiman(سليمان) had.
And you would find that many quotes and movements; they attach themselves to Sulaiman(سليمان).
Many of these secret orders; they claim that they go back to Sulaiman(سليمان).
And the most famous of them, is the Masonic movement; Al-Masoniyyah(الماسونيه); the Freemasons.
You would find that the concept of the temple; the Temple of Solomon,
is something that is central or it is very influential, and the ideology of the Freemasons.
Also movements like the Kabalah(كباله) and some of these other, a mystical Jewish cults;
they practice magic which they claim, they have learned from Sulaiman(سليمان) and they claim that the lineage goes back to Sulaiman(سليمان).
Now there is some truth that, there is magic, that goes back in lineage to some very early Jews; but it does not go back to Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
It all goes back to where?
Where did the Jews learned this magic, that some of which still exists until now?
And it's very powerful magic, we're not talking about tricks;
where you hide a coin, and you bring it out from somewhere, or you bring something out of the hat.
We're not talking about those tricks which they fool the kids with.
We're talking about some serious magic that could do some serious harm.
Where was that learned from?
We know that, in the time of Firaun(فرعون), there was some magic.
But Allah-u-Aalam(اللَّهُ أَعْلمَ)! Even though, it was very powerful magic.
But it was limited to the field of optical illusion.
Because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَسَحَرُوٓاْ أَعْيُنَ ٱلنَّاسِ
They have committed magic to the eyes of people.
But we're talking about some other magic; that could influence the psychology and the spirit of people.
Where was that learned?
In Babel?
And how did they get it from Babel?
We know from the history that the kingdom of the Jews was destroyed by who?
Nabukhal-Nasr(نبوخل نصر);
The Babylonian kingdom; they defeated the Jews in the Holy Land, and they broke up their kingdom.
Not only that, they took them as slaves back to Iraq in Babel; in Babylon.
They took them back to Babel.
And the Jews were cut off from the true religion of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
They were cut off from the scripture for quite a while.
And they were under the influence, and the dictatorship, and the oppression, and the tyranny of the Babylonians.
And that is where, a lot of the distortion, that happened to the religion of Judaism, that is where, it occurred; it occurred in Babel.
Where was the Talmud(تلمود) written, and Who wrote it?
It was written by the 70 rabbis who were in; Babylon.
And now, that is the law and the centre of focus of the Yahood( يهود) now.
They have left the Torah(توراة), and they're following the Talmud(تلمود).
And the Talmud(تلمود) was written by the rabbis, who were influenced by the regime and the environment in Babylon.
So if you read about this history; you find that Babylon is associated to it, all.
There's a lot of association with Babylon.
At-Talmud(التّلمود) came out of there, and magic, and these secret orders; they came from Babylon, rather than from Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان).
Even though, they attribute it to Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان).
The other point; issue of the temple.
This temple of Sulaiman(سليمان) is a myth.
There is no such thing called Temple of Sulaiman(سليمان).
The one who built the Masjid(مسجد) was who?
Yaqoobعليه السلام.
By the Nus(نص), by the Hadith(حديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ
Abu Dhar رضي الله عنه came to Rasool Allah ﷺ, and said; What was the first house established for the worship of Allah?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said; Al-Masjid Al-Haram(المسجد الحرام);
Al-Qa'bah(الكعبه).
And then he said; And then what? Rasool Allah ﷺ said;
اَلْمَسْجِدْ الْاَقْصى وَبَيْنَهُمَا اَرْبَعِيْنَ عَاماً
Then, the Masjid(مسجد) of Al-Aqsa(الاقصى); Jerusalem and between them was 40 years.
40 years is the time between Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) and Yaqoobعليه السلام.
So, Yaqoob(يعقوب) is the one who built the Masjid(مسجد), or established it.
What was the role of Sulaiman(سليمان)?
Sulaimanعليه السلام; he is the one who expanded the Masjid(مسجد), and built it in its great form.
Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) is the one, who erected the Masjid(مسجد) and expanded it during his kingdom.
It was not a temple; it was a Masjid(مسجد); established for the worship of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
It's a Masjid(مسجد); the Mosque.
So this myth of the Temple of Sulaiman(سليمان), and all of this mythology is attached to it, and superstition and power; it's unreal.
There was a Masjid(مسجد).
Now, let's read from Surat-ul-Baqarah(سورةالبقره), Ayah(آية); which is 101;
لَمَّا جَآءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مِّنْ عِندِ ٱللَّهِ مُصَدِّقٌ لِّمَا مَعَهُمْ نَبَذَ فَرِيقٌ مِّنَ ٱلَّذِينَ أُوتُواْ ٱلْكِتَٰبَ كِتَٰبَ ٱللَّهِ وَرَآءَ ظُهُورِهِمْ كَأَنَّهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ۝
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; And when they are came to them; a messenger from Allah, came to who?
This talking about Al-Yahood(اليهود); the Jews.
And when there came to them; a messenger from Allah; confirming what was sent to them;
a party of those who were given the Scripture; threw away the book of Allah behind their backs, as if they did not know.
So they threw away the book of Allah.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ came, because they don't want to follow him.
And what did they follow?
وَاتَّبَعُوا مَا تَتْلُو الشَّيَاطِينُ عَلَىٰ مُلْكِ سُلَيْمَانَ ۖ
And they followed what the devils gave out in the lifetime of Sulaiman(سليمان).
What is this talking about?
The devils were teaching the people magic.
Ash-Shayateen(الشَّيَاطِين); the devils were teaching the people magic; before the time of Sulaiman(سليمان) and during the kingdom of Sulaiman(سليمان).
As-suddi(السّدّى); in his Tafseer(تفسير) of this Ayah(آية), he says;
Sulaiman(سليمان) came to know; that the devils are teaching people magic.
So he gathered all of their manuals and books.
He took them away from the people.
Because the people used to record, what they would learn from the devils.
Sulaiman(سليمان) took away all of those manuals and books.
And he made a law that, whoever learns magic, or practices Magic, or teaches magic will be executed.
And he took away all of these books and manuals and he buried them.
As the story goes, under his throne; he buried them.
To get rid of them; he buried them.
And he made a law in his time that nobody should learn, or teach, or practice magic.
This is from Shayateen(شَيَاطِين).
What happened, when Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) passed away,
Ash-Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ); Iblees(ابليس) came to the people in the form of a human being, and he said;
Do you know, where Sulaiman(سليمان) used to get his power from?
The devils are the ones, who used to teach him, and I'll show you the proof.
Go and dig under his throne, and see what you will find.
They were to dig into the throne; they saw the manuals and the books of magic.
So they made a rumor, and they said that; Sulaiman(سليمان); this is how he used to control the Jinn(جِن),
and this is how he achieved all of that power; it is through magic.
And that's how, they propagated this false rumor against Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان).
So, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى responds to this claim, and says;
وَمَا كَفَرَ سُلَيْمَانُ
Sulaiman(سليمان) has not committed Kuffr(كفر); Sulaiman(سليمان) did not disbelief.
This part of the Ayah(آية) tells us two things.
First of all it tells us that, Sulaiman(سليمان) did not commit disbelief, and it tells us that, Sahar(سَحَر); magic; what is it considered?
It's considered to be Kuffr(كفر); is considered to be disbelief.
Because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَمَا كَفَرَ سُلَيْمَانُ
Sulaiman(سليمان) did not disbelief.
This magic is not from him; because magic is disbelief, and Sulaimanعليه السلام did not disbelief.
وَمَا كَفَرَ سُلَيْمَانُ وَلَٰكِنَّ الشَّيَاطِينَ كَفَرُوا
But the devils are the ones, who disbelieved.
يُعَلِّمُونَ النَّاسَ السِّحْرَ
Teaching men magic.
Who are the ones, who are teaching magic?
The devils.
وَمَا أُنزِلَ عَلَى الْمَلَكَيْنِ
And what was revealed to the two angels.
And we'll Get into this In Sha' Allah(ان شاء الله)!
وَمَا أُنزِلَ عَلَى الْمَلَكَيْنِ
Now, in Qur'an; Allahسُبحانه وتعالى rarely mentions places.
Unless, there is a reason for mentioning a locality or a place.
The Book of Allah is a book of guidance.
So you don't find a lot of dates, and numbers, and chronological order of events, and places, and like you would find in the old testament or new testament.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَمَا أُنزِلَ عَلَى الْمَلَكَيْنِ
Where?
Bi'Babila(بِبَابِلَ);
In Babil(بَابِل).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى mentioned the place over here in the Ayah(آية).
And Allah-u-Aalam(اللَّهُ أَعْلمَ)! The reason is because all of this magic, or secret orders, or distorted teachings came out of Babil(بَابِل).
And we know that, through history, and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى wanted to record that in Qur'an; so that, we would learn.
Where the source of all of this came from?
It came from Babil(بَابِل).
Because; without reading Qur'an, by just reading the history, and books that deal with this; you would be able to see, the association with Babil(بَابِل).
So when you read it in Qur'an, it's an amazing thing to see; how Allahسُبحانه وتعالى tie this into Babil(بَابِل).
And that, then gives us the complete picture of what happened.
Because you could do readings; the secular reading on one side on the history and what was happening.
And then when you read Qur'an; it would put everything in perspective for you.
Because Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَمَا أُنزِلَ عَلَى الْمَلَكَيْنِ بِبَابِلَ
What was revealed to the angels in Babil(بَابِل).
هَارُوتَ وَمَارُوتَ ۚ
Harut(هاروت) and Marut(ماروت).
The Mufassireen(مفسرين) have a few opinions, and they could be contradictory to each other.
I'll mention one; that was mentioned by a few of the Mufassireen(مفسرين) and seems to fit the Ayah(آية) most.
And that is; that Harut(هاروت) and Marut(ماروت) were two angels, who descended to Babil(بَابِل), and they were teaching people magic.
These two angels were teaching people magic.
And they were doing it with the permission of Allahسُبحانه وتعالى by the will of Allah.
We will read the Ayah(آية) and then, elaborate on this a little bit.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَلَٰكِنَّ الشَّيَاطِينَ كَفَرُوا يُعَلِّمُونَ النَّاسَ السِّحْرَ وَمَا أُنزِلَ عَلَى الْمَلَكَيْنِ بِبَابِلَ هَارُوتَ وَمَارُوتَ ۚ
وَمَا يُعَلِّمَانِ مِنْ أَحَدٍ حَتَّىٰ يَقُولَا إِنَّمَا نَحْنُ فِتْنَةٌ فَلَا تَكْفُرْ ۖ
But the devils disbelieved; teaching men magic, and such things that came down at Babylon to the two angels Harut(هاروت) and Marut(ماروت);
but neither of these two angels taught anyone such things until, they said;
We are only for a trial, so disbelieve not.
These two Angels descended to Babil(بَابِل), and they knew about magic; they knew this knowledge of magic.
And people would come to them to learn.
The angels would tell them; This knowledge that we are offering is Kuffr(كفر).
So do not learn it; because this is Fitnah(فِتْنَه).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى wanted this to be a test.
Knowledge; that is offered for you, but you shouldn't learn it.
That's, what it's about.
It's a test from Allahسُبحانه وتعالى.
Here is knowledge; you're not supposed to learn it.
And this is knowledge that will make you disbelieve in Allah.
And it's offered; This is the address; you want to go and learn it.
But the angels would not offer it to anyone until, they would tell him;
إِنَّمَا نَحْنُ فِتْنَةٌ فَلَا تَكْفُرْ ۖ
This is a Fitnah(فِتْنَه); so do not disbelief.
The other stories, that are mentioned in the book of Tafseer(تفسیر) is that,
these two angels; actually, the test was for them.
They say that, these two angels said; How come these people are sinning?
So Allahسُبحانه وتعالى said; go down to earth and Allah put in them the shahawat(شهوات) of a human being; the desires of a human being.
And when Allah put in them the desires of the human being; they committed sins, and they started practicing magic.
But this does not seem to make sense.
Because we know that the angels;
لَّا يَعْصُونَ ٱللَّهَ مَآ أَمَرَهُمْ وَيَفْعَلُونَ مَا يُؤْمَرُونَ۝
The angels did not disobey the orders of Allah, and they do what Allah has ordered them.
So it doesn't seem to make sense, especially that there is no evidence to support it.
If we would go with the literal meaning of the Ayah(آية);
it would mean that, these are two angels who came down with the permission of Allah;
to test the people, and to offer them something that is Kuffr(كفر), and they should not learn it.
This knowledge was learned by a faction of Al-Yahood(اليهود); the Jews,
and it has been inherited from generation to generation through secret orders, and part of that magic still exists until now.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has told us one effect of such brand or type of magic.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
فَيَتَعَلَّمُونَ مِنْهُمَا مَا يُفَرِّقُونَ بِهِ بَيْنَ الْمَرْءِ وَزَوْجِهِ ۚ
They learn from these angels; what could cause separation between man and his wife.
This is a kind of magic.
It's a magic spell; that is cast on the husband or the wife.
And it would cause hatred in the heart of the husband or the wife.
And it would make it unbearable.
And eventually it would cause divorce, separation.
And this exists, and I personally happen to know a few cases; firsthand knowledge of some cases where this happened.
It is true that this exists, but also, it is true that many people take it out of context.
And whenever there's a problem between husband and wife, they hang it on magic.
They said; There's magic between them, and that's not true.
There are a few cases and we should not always say that there's magic between them, and that's why there's a problem;
No!
Sometimes, it's magic, sometimes it's uncompatibility of two persons.
But this type of magic is not only limited to putting these differences between husband and wife, it could cause some other harm.
And the way it's done, they have to have a part of your body;
a hair, a nail with the assistance of the Jinn(جِن) would wrap it in what is Uqda(عقده), Al-Aqd(العقد).
And they would wrap it with that part of your body in it.
And that is what would cause this problem or magic to take effect.
And they would throw it somewhere.
And when this type of magic was done on Rasool Allah ﷺ according to the authentic Ahadith(احاديث);
one of the Yahood(يهود) has done a magic spell on Rasool Allah ﷺ.
He threw it; where did he throw it?
He threw it in a well.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ was suffering from that magic.
Jibreel عليه السلام came to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said;
that it is in this well, so they retrieved that out of the well, and they opened it up and the magic was released.
So that Uqdah(عقده); Uqdah(عقده) means a knot, that knot has to be released for the magic to be released.
Sometimes they throw it in the ocean, or they bury it in the desert.
That's how difficult it could be.
But because this seems to be power, that is in the hands of the magician, and seems to be supernatural abilities.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is telling us;
وَمَا هُم بِضَارِّينَ بِهِ مِنْ أَحَدٍ إِلَّا بِإِذْنِ اللَّهِ ۚ
And they would not harm anyone except by Allah's leave.
So Allah Is telling us that, this is not power in the hands of the magicians that Allahسُبحانه وتعالى is not able to control.
Allah Is telling us that everything that is happening is, by His Mashee'ah(مشيه) by His will, as a test.
And for us it is a test because; we need to read Al-Mu'awwidhat(معوذات), and we need to read Ayat-Al-Kursi(آيت الكرسى), and we need to read what will save us, from such things.
So it is just like any other disease that exists.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has created Ad-Da'(الدّاء), and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى created Ad-Dawa'(الدَّواء).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى created the illness, and Allahسُبحانه وتعالى created the cure.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says;
ما من داء الا له دواء
Every illness Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has created the cure for.
So, there's a cure for cancer; there's a cure for AIDS; there is a cure for everything.
علمه من علمه وجهله من جهله
Some people would know it, and some people won't.
It's knowledge that needs to be investigated.
This is a disease or an illness; this issue of magic; and there is a cure for it. And the cure is;
قُلۡ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ ٱلۡفَلَقِ۝
And;
قُلۡ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ ٱلنَّاسِ۝
And the other types of Isti'adha(استعاذه) that Rasool Allah ﷺ would do, and Ayat-Al-Kursi(آيت الكرسى).
And that's why, we need to always practice repeating these Adiyyah(ادعیۃ).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَيَتَعَلَّمُونَ مَا يَضُرُّهُمْ وَلَا يَنفَعُهُمْ ۚ
The Magician would think that by learning this knowledge; they could benefit.
Person goes to the magician thinks that the magician could benefit them.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; And they learn; what harms them, and profits them not.
So, Allahسُبحانه وتعالى tells us that; magic is purely harm and there is no benefit in it, whatsoever.
Whatsoever there's no benefit in it.
And when Ibn-Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) talks about the suffering and the misery; the magicians go through when they follow this path; you would be amazed.
Don't think that the devils teach them this knowledge for free.
They pay for it.
And they pay for it, in the worst ways.
And when Ibn-Taymiyyah(ابن تيميه) talks about the rituals; the magicians go through, before they are incepted in the ranks of the magicians;
it is things, that would make the hair on your body stand.
They would make them drink the blood of menstrual.
They would make them eat frogs, and snakes, and insects.
They would make them right Ayaat(آيات) of Qur'an with blood and step over it.
They would make them make Istinja(استنجا) with pages of Qur'an.
They would make them make Sujood(سجود) to the devils.
They would make them make Sujood(سجود) to idols.
These are rituals that the magicians have to go through, before they get the assistance of the Jinn(جِن).
They do not offer their services for free.
Jinn(جِن) do not offer their services for free.
The right way to heal is by reading Qur'an.
And by the Shuyukh who read Qur'an, that is a valid way because;
فِيْهِ شِفَاء
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; In Qur'an is healing.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى then says;
وَلَقَدْ عَلِمُوا لَمَنِ اشْتَرَاهُ مَا لَهُ فِي الآخِرَةِ مِنْ خَلاقٍ وَلَبِئْسَ مَا شَرَوْا بِهِ أَنْفُسَهُمْ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ۝
And indeed, they knew that the buyers of it; magic, would have no share in the here after, and how bad indeed was that, for which they sold their own selves.
Because the magician sells himself, if they but knew.
وَلَوْ أَنَّهُمْ آمَنُوا وَاتَّقَوْا لَمَثُوبَةٌ مِنْ عِنْدِ اللَّهِ خَيْرٌ
And if they had believed and guarded themselves from evil, and kept their duty to Allah;
far better would have been the reward from their Lord if they but knew.
So from these Ayaat(آيات); the Sahabahرضى الله عنهم and also the Ahadith(احاديث) of Rasool Ullah;
the Sahabahرضى الله عنهم reached to the conclusion that, magic is;
كفر مخرج عن الملة
It is an act that will take a person out of the fold of Islam.
And that is why, Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب); he sent out messages to the Islamic States or the governance through Wilayat(ولايات) saying;
اقتلوا كل ساحر
Kill any magician.
And one of the Sahabah(صحابه) said; we found three magicians and we executed them.
So the Ulama(عُلَمَا) say that, this is the Hadd(حدّ) of magic, it is execution.
Because wallahi(ولله) you know stories of how magicians harm people.
You would say that this is a little punishment for them.
I mean, they have destroyed, they have broken houses, and they have caused harm.
The amazing thing that nowadays, this particular type of knowledge; where is it most widespread, in the Muslim world.?
It does exist everywhere else, but it's quite widespread in the Muslim world.
And obviously reason is; work of Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ).
That is where he wants to break up families.
Because, we know from the Hadith(حديث) of Rasool Allah ﷺ that; Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) sets his throne on water,
and then the devils come and report to him, and everyone brings in a report
and Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) tells him; sit down! Sit down! Sit down!
And then eventually, one would come and say; I have good news for you.
I did not leave the husband and wife, until I separated them.
Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) would say; You are the one, come and sit next to me.
Breaking up the families is Amal-Ash-Shaytan(عَمَلَ الشَّيْطَانْ).
And that is why, Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) tries to cause all of these fitan(فتن) among the Muslims in General.
يَنزَغُ بَيْنَهُمْ ۚ
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَقُل لِّعِبَادِى يَقُولُواْ ٱلَّتِى هِىَ أَحْسَنُ ۚ إِنَّ ٱلشَّيْطَٰنَ يَنزَغُ بَيْنَهُمْ ۚ
Tell my servants; the Muslims to say a good word.
Why?
Because Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) tries to plant disunity among them.
So one of the solutions to counter that, is to say good word.
Because, our words, or arms, or weapon in the hands of Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ).
He takes that word, and he makes Su'adh-Dhan(سؤذن) in the heart of the other person; bad suspicion.
And that's how problems starts.
Usually problems start because of what?
Words.
So Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
وَقُل لِّعِبَادِى يَقُولُواْ ٱلَّتِى هِىَ أَحْسَنُ ۚ
Tell my servants to say the good word.
If we would just monitor our words; believe me all of these problems would cease to exist.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has fulfilled his Dua(دُعَا) when he said;
هَبْ لِي مُلْكًا لَّا يَنبَغِي لِأَحَدٍ مِّن بَعْدِي ۖ
He said; Oh Allah! Give me a kingdom that will occur to nobody, after me.
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى gave him a unique kingdom.
And part of the uniqueness of the kingdom of Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) is; he has control over Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين).
And Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام would put Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين) under slave labour.
They would work for him in what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى has called;
عَذَابٌ مُّهِينٌ۝
He would have them work, and serves him, and he would command them to do very difficult tasks.
This is what Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has given Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) the ability to do.
So, it's a service for Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) and in the same time, it's a punishment for Shayateen(شَيَاطِين).
They had to do the slave labour for him.
But Al-Yahood(اليهود); they accused Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) of being influenced by Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين), and being controlled by Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين).
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام; he had this control over Al-Jinn(الجِن).
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام; when he passed away; the Jinn(جِن) continued working for him and the Shayateen(شَيَاطِين); even though, he was already dead.
Because he was kneeling on his cane, and he was dead.
But the Shayateen(شَيَاطِين) used to think that he was alive.
Even though, he already passed away.
And termites were eating from his cane from the inside, and the cane was going hollow, but he was still supported by his cane, sitting on his throne.
And then when the termites kept on drilling through the cane and the cane broke down; then Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام fell down.
Only then did the Jinn(جِن), and Shayateen(شَيَاطِين) realize that Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام was dead.
But before that, they continued serving and going through that slave labour.
Because, they were still seeing Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) sitting on his Arsh(عرش); on his throne.
And Allahسُبحانه وتعالى Has mentioned this in Qur'an; to refute the claims of Al-Yahood(اليهود)
that Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) was controlled or influenced by the Jinn(جِن).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
فَلَمَّا قَضَيْنَا عَلَيْهِ ٱلْمَوْتَ مَا دَلَّهُمْ عَلَىٰ مَوْتِهِۦٓ إِلَّا دَآبَّةُ ٱلْأَرْضِ تَأْكُلُ مِنسَأَتَهُۥ ۖ
فَلَمَّاا خَرَّ تَبَيَّنَتِ ٱلْجِنُّ أَن لَّوْ كَانُواْ يَعْلَمُونَ ٱلْغَيْبَ مَا لَبِثُواْ فِى ٱلْعَذَابِ ٱلْمُهِينِ۝
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says;
Then when We decreed death for him; Sulaiman(سليمان); nothing informed them the Jinn(جِن) of his death except a little worm of the earth,
which kept slowly knowing away at his stick.
So when he fell down the Jinn(جِن) saw clearly, that if they had known the unseen they would not have stayed in the humiliating torment.
This Ayah(آية) response the two things.
First of all, it is to respond to the claim that the Jinn(جِن) were influencing Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
And number two; it responds to the claim that the Jinn(جِن) know Al-Ghaib(الغيب).
The Jinn(جِن); they do not know Al-Ghaib(الغيب).
And Al-Kahanah (الكهنه) and As-Saharah(السّحره); the magician's, and the fortune tellers; they depend on a Al-Jin(الجِن)
and they claim that Jinn(جِن) know the future.
And since we have connection with the Jinn(جِن); We can know, until what will happen in the future.
But Allahسُبحانه وتعالى says; If the Jinn(جِن) knew Al-Ghaib(الغيب); if they knew the unseen; they wouldn't have remained in this punishment.
Because the kind of tasks that Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) was putting them through;
was a form of punishment and humiliation for Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين) and Al-Jinn(الجِن).
And they kept on doing it even though Sayidina Sulaiman(سيدنا سليمان) was dead.
And this is a proof that Al-Jinn(الجِن) and Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين); they do not know Al-Ghaib(الغيب).
They do not know the unseen.
The Jinn(جِن); they do not have any knowledge, whatsoever about the unseen except what they steal from the conversation.
When the eavesdrop on the angels, that's the only information that they have.
And they mix one piece of truth with 99 lies.
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام passed away.
And that's when the Jinn(جِن) realized that they have been working, overtime.
And they know that he's the only human being who has control over us.
So as soon as Sulaimanعليه السلام passed away; they went to their normal jobs of the pre Sulaimanic era, and that is to deviate people.
Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام did not have control over all of the Jinn(جِن) and Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين).
Allahسُبحانه وتعالى put under his control some of Al-Jinn(الجِن) and Ash-Shayateen(اَلشَّيَاطِين).
This is the story of Sayidina Sulaimanعليه السلام.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تسلیما کثیرا